parenting what does game b have to think
about
how children are raised wow how they
relate to their parents and how
spouses relate to each other all right
so here's here's here's what i think is
probably the
the easiest piece so i'm going to play a
game where i'm just going to try to say
the thing that i think is the most
fundamental and not do a lot more
because there's a lot
great so if you have an intuitive sense
that the relationship between parent and
child
has a strong fundamental asymmetry
like it's a it's a relationship between
master and student or it's a
relationship between boss and employee
then game b would will have some
surprises for you
that within the game b context
there and remember humility is super
important there is a
deep deep awareness of the degree to
which
really effective parenting has a sense
of symmetry which is to say and here's
the way that i've said it to people
and i have a one-year-old daughter so
this is like very concrete for me
i am aware that she
is a fully realized soul at least as
rich and fully realized as i right as a
human being
we are equal i happen to have
been in a body that's gone around the
sun many more times than her particular
body so when it comes to a lot of the
kinds of things that have to do with how
bodies maneuver into time and space
i've got a lot more experience and so i
play a particular role
of asymmetry in terms of supporting her
building the capacity
in herself to become more capable of
being in the world and notice by the way
what i said there i said supporting her
and building the capacity in herself i
don't mean
impressing the things that i've learned
on her
propositionally top down because that
gets in the way that's what a teacher
a bad teacher does to a student you're
not learning how to fish i'm just giving
you the fish in this
metaphor but at the same time
i certainly have noticed that in terms
of my own developmental journey my own
building of integrity in myself am i on
learning and growing
she has this much to teach me in terms
of like liminality
she's the master of limitality because
she really is coming with the child's
mind to reality
and so if i look at that and say wow so
what's really happening here is that we
are
teaching each other this question of
meaningfulness
and i'm opening myself up to the
possibility of how
deeply she can change me and honoring
the responsibility i have of how deeply
she's opening herself up to the
possibility of how much i can change her
and we are now peers collaborating in
this crazy [ __ ] show
of parenting child family and reality
that's a game b way of looking at that
problem